Joe Mendez-Hughes

Website | LinkedIn | joemendezhughes@gmail.com | 1-480-220-8939 | Phoenix, AZ | U.S. Citizen

SUMMARY

Real-world experienced AI engineer who has built real AI/ML models and applications in production environments.

SKILLS

Python | Natural Language Processing (NLP) | Large Language Models (LLMs) | Generative AI | RAGs | GANs | PyTorch | APIs | Git | AWS/GCP | SQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SENIOR AI ENGINEER

Dynamo Technologies, Washington, DC September 2023 - May 2024

- Designed and implemented AI reporting systems, employing trend analysis and machine learning, reducing operational costs significantly.
- Crafted advanced predictive analytics models, using machine learning to forecast trends and providing agencies with the ability to mobilize accordingly and distribute personnel accurately.
- Engineered advanced AI tools that analyzed vast, complex datasets, delivering critical health and support metrics for children and adults across county, state, and national levels.
- Led the charge in refining AI reporting accuracy through iterative machine learning models, turning raw data into crystal-clear insights.
- Architected Al-driven analytics into the business intelligence platform, driving a 35% increase in data-driven decision-making and reducing manual reporting by 50%.

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Deep Cloud IQ, New York, NY July 2021 - September 2023

- Engineered a robust sentiment analysis tracker, empowering administrators to detect early signs of disengagement or distress, allowing for timely interventions.
- Spearheaded the creation of a dynamic ML pipeline. Utilizing performance data, this tool identified areas of struggle and offered targeted strategies to elevate students to their full potential.
- Worked with Google engineers and Google provided data sets, crafting a cutting-edge NLP pipeline.
- Created a suite of software that included chat applications, analytical tools, and administrative tools tuned with machine learning that offered an all-encompassing view of student health and behavior.
- Optimized data processing, storage, and retrieval, reducing latency and providing real-time insights.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Millennial Shift Technologies, Phoenix, AZ October 2020 – June 2021

Delivered complex integrations by developing and deploying SOAP and REST APIs.

JR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aristocrat - Independent Contractor, Las Vegas, NV February 2018 - May 2020

Assisted in the development and maintenance of back-end services for applications.

EDUCATION

College of Southern Nevada Studied: Computer Science